Everybody, we are excited to be joined
by the Ravens latest draft pick, Elijah
Serat. Uh, as we've done the last few
days, if you could please use the raise
hand function if you have a question for
Elijah. Uh, we'll kick things off and
get started.
>> With who?
>> Well, no one raised their hand yet, so
anybody who has a question, have at it.
Jameson, thank you.
>> Um, Elijah, uh, coming from, uh, St.
Francis, uh, how much does this
homecoming mean to you,
>> man? It means a lot. It's crazy just how
things work out like that. I feel like
it's just a meant to be moment, man.
Being in St. at St. Francis Academy, it
taught me so much. Grew me up as a man
and I had a lot of great experiences
there. So, I'm I'm forever grateful that
I can go back there and play some play
ball at the best level now.
>> Go with Brian Wacker and then Ryan Mink.
Hey, Elijah. Uh, congrats. And just, um,
to kind of carry off of that, you
thought about what it's going to be like
to catch passes from Lamar Jackson. How
closely have you watched this team?
Obviously, as somebody who, you know,
played here in high school.
>> Yeah, I've watched I've watched many,
many of the Raven games, man. Lamar
Jackson's one of the best one of the
best players in the NFL, man. And I just
want to be able to do my part on the
field so he can trust me and I can go
out there and make plays for him and
make his job easy.
Congratulations,
Elijah. Uh, just want to ask you about
your contested catch ability. Kind of
what's your your mindset when the ball's
in the air and then back shoulder
throws. You and Mendoza had great
connection there. Can you talk about how
how you uh are so good at making those
catches?
>> Yeah. Um, and my mindset is just anytime
the ball's in the air that it's mine. No
matter if I'm uncovering, no matter if I
have one person on me, two person on me,
just as a receiver, if you want to be
great, you got to have that mindset. So,
whatever pass it is, I feel like I can
make it. And um the back shoulders
throws, it's something that's a big
strength of my game. I've been able to
do it um just about every year in
college. Thankfully, I've had lots of
great quarterbacks, like you said,
Fernando done a a great job of putting
it where I need to be. And my my thing
with the back shoulders is just you're
always trying to win over top and then
it's kind of if you know, it's a feel.
It's a field thing and then it's just a
trust between you and the quarterback.
And that just happens doesn't happen
overnight. Just happens with reps
throughout camp and practices. That's
all it is. Go to Gianna Han and then Sam
Con, please.
>> Congratulations. Um, I was wondering
when did the nickname Waffle House start
to come about? What was your reaction to
it? And can you just tell us a little
bit about why you were so open in
college? Why you were so successful at
that?
>> Yeah. Um, it really started at um my
sophomore year at JMU. Um, I was feel
like every third down or something, they
would give me the ball and I would
convert on it. And then my dad was he
went on social media talking about he's
always open Waffle House or something.
not too many people seeing it. And fast
forward to uh my junior year at Indiana,
they it was like a summer interview. I
was just doing some media and they were
like, "What's your nickname?" And then I
kind of said it trolling, not thinking
anything of it. And then next thing I
know, hours later, it's blowing up on
Twitter and here we are today. Uh I got
merch and everything for it's a cool
nickname, but it's also a mindset, too.
Like I like I said, those contested
catches, I always feel like I'm open.
It's just just a mentality that I have.
>> Hey, Elijah. Congratulations, man. Um,
know you're a former basketball player
and as a contested catch guy, just
anything you could tell us or share
about your your old basketball career
and maybe how that kind of translated or
helped you become the receiver you are.
>> Yeah, I love basketball. It was my my
first sport. I for real for real. I love
I love basketball. Um, but all the just
playing different sports, any different
sport, I feel like it kind of translates
into somehow a different sport. Like
soccer, it helps your feet. basketball
just body movements, body control. I
feel like it I feel like it helps you a
lot on the field and just with the
contestant catches with me running
routes, just being on balance if
someone's trying to push me and stuff
like that. So, it definitely translates
I feel like.
>> Go to Kyle Goon, please.
>> Hey Elijah, welcome back. Um, you know,
you you made the jump from JMU to
Indiana and obviously had the highest
success at the highest level college.
What about that journey makes you
believe that you can make the jump to
the NFL?
>> Yeah. Um, just I've been able to prove
it um each step uh each step that I've
been to. I've been grateful to have a
lot of coach, a lot of great coaches, a
lot of great players around me. But I
feel like it's just the work that you
put in is what you're going to get out
of it, man. And my mindset, I'm still
going to have that same chip on my
shoulder that I had as my freshman year
coming out of high school, man. Just go
out there. I'm at ground zero right now.
I got like I got to prove everything.
So, it's just going out there, going to
work, and proving it every single day.
Now,
>> uh Jonah Schaefer.
>> Hey, Elijah. Congrats, man. Uh I wanted
to know whether you've talked with the
Ravens at all or I guess other teams
around the NFL about where maybe they
see you fitting best at this next level
because I know, you know, you worked
primarily outside. Um but just, you
know, your your openness to to maybe
becoming more of a slot guy or what kind
of uh what kind of vision teams have had
for you and specifically the Ravens?
>> Yeah. Um, a lot of teams that I've
talked to, Ravens included, they kind of
see me playing all three spots. You
know, I traditionally played outside,
played more X in college, but a lot of
teams see me as a big slot guy, guy who
can work work option routes, work the
zones, middle of the field and stuff
like that. And they also see me as a Z
receiver who can move around, do some
motion, do some blocking and stuff. So,
I'm just going to try to soak as much
game as I can from from the people that
I got in the room already, all the
coaches, all the all the players in the
organization, and just go to work, study
my plays, and just be able to earn earn
the guys trust. is is my main thing. I
earn the trust. I feel like I that's a
good foot to start off on.
>> All right, we'll go to Jeff Zerbeck and
then close it out with Ryan Mink,
please.
>> Elijah, were you did you take part in
the Ravens pro local proday here? And if
not, where how would you describe your
interaction with the Ravens during this
pre-draft process? And did you think
they were a potential suitor going into
this day?
>> Yeah, I didn't I didn't go come up to
the local day just with the timing and
everything of our schedules. We uh we
couldn't make it work. We talked about
doing it um and stuff, but I after
proday um I've talked to a receiver
coach. We got on the um got in the film
room, did some board work for for a
little for a long while was just talking
chopping it up. So, I knew it was a I
knew it was an opportunity um that I
could go there and I'm I'm grateful,
man. Like I'm so happy. I'm so happy and
blessed to be here in this great
organization that I've been been a fan
of since I was since I was young. Just
watching so many legends play through
that organization. So, I'm excited to go
in there and just and do my part.
>> Elijah, the Ravens drafted Jacobe Lane
uh with their third round pick.
Back-to-back wide receivers, kind of big
body contested catch guys. What's it
like coming into the league with another
another wide receiver like that?
>> Yeah, I'm grateful for it, man. We're
able to push each other. We're able to
just get each other better every single
day. Me and him, we we we became friends
at the combine. That was my first time
meeting him. So, he's real cool real
cool dude. We follow each other on
socials after after that. So, it's it's
crazy that we teamed up together, man.
But, I'm excited for him and I'm sure
he's excited for me. I'm ready to get to
work with him.
>> All right. Well, thank you very much
everybody, Elijah. We appreciate you
joining us today. Congratulations on
being drafted by the Ravens and we look
forward to seeing you here soon.
>> Yeah. Thank you guys. Guys, have a good
one.